# 转圈 涮涮
Circling in the water
# 你看看 冰水
Look at the ice water
# 没有这么折磨的
Not one tortures like you
# 这就对了
now it's right
# 后(六)宫粉黛无颜色 贵妃鸡
Gui Fei Chicken makes all other chickens look less intriguing
# 三黄鸡 在家其实用仔鸡也行
San Huang chicken at home actually will do with normal chickens
# 鸡腿都行 对 没错
Drumsticks are fine, right?
# 我先拿盐搓 入味
I rub it with salt to add some flavor
# 烹调前加味 腌制一下
Add flavor before cooking and marinate
# 这是一个很传统的老菜
This is a very traditional old dish
# 现在做的人也不多了
There are not many people who can cook it now
# 我记得当年北京饭店就有过
I remember the Beijing Hotel used to serve this
# 我们在原有基础上我们稍微改良改良
We improved slightly on the basis of the original
# 更适应现代人的是需求
To make it more suitable for modern people’s demand
# 你看我们把这个鸡就抓吧抓吧
You see, let's rub this chicken
# 就差不多了
It's almost done
# 小葱把它装到鸡肚子里边了
Put shallots in the chicken’s belly
# 加两片姜 提个味
Add two slices of ginger to bring out the taste
# 肛门这块 我再把这块剌了去
The anus part, I will chop this part out
# 细节是吧 细节 这东西不能要
The details are very important, this can not be used
# 拿牙签一别 防止小葱漏出来
Take a toothpick and prevent the green onions from leaking out
# 再来一根 一着热它就紧实了
Let’s get another one, it will become firm when heated
# 这就行了是吧
That's all right
# 开始洗澡了 这桶够大
I'm giving the chicken a bath. This bucket is big enough
# 转圈 涮涮
Circling in the water
# 你看看冰水
Look at the ice water
# 这样一下把这个鸡皮就激脆了
This will make the chicken skin crispy
# 为什么有时候说脆皮鸡那皮不够脆
Why is it sometimes said that the crispy chicken skin is not crispy enough
# 其实就没经过这（一步）
Actually, they didn’t go through this (step)
# 这爪子怎么不去 多碍事儿
Why didn’t you get rid of this chicken claw?
# 那就不要了得了
Then let’s get rid of it
# 这行了  又来一次
This is done   came again
# 师父这一共得几次
Master got a few times in total
# 三次就行 三次是吧
Three times, three times, right?
# 稍微烫一下是吧
blench it a bit, right?
# 又下了冰水了
Ice water again
# 一次比一次鼓 越来越紧实 更加脆
It’s are getting tighter and crisper every time
# 我们控控水 又来一次
We drain out the water again
# 你折磨这小鸡 给折磨的够呛
You’ve tortured the chick enough
# 贵妃鸡没有这么折磨的
There is no one torture like you
# 好了 越来越来越重了这鸡
Okay, this chicken is getting heavier and heavier
# 再来一下
One more time
# 网友朋友们这个在家做的凉透了
Netizens and friends, cool it down thoroughly when you cook at home
# 这样的话鸡皮才脆
In this way, the chicken skin is crispy
# 鸡泡上 先下料
Soak the chicken first
# 师父您给介绍介绍这几个料吧
Master, please introduce these ingredients
# 枣 大枣
Dates, big dates
# 干柠檬片
Dried lemon slices
# 香叶
bayleave
# 海米虾干
Dried shrimp
# 枸杞子 干贝
Chinese Goji scallops
# 栀子 花椒
Gardenia Pepper
# 先煮它一会 小焦你给加上味吧
Let’s cook it for a while. Jiao season it a bit
# 我把这鸡爪子给它斩一斩
I cut this chicken claw
# 你还给贵妃修脚 修一修
You even get to trim foot for Gui Fei
# 然后我把这个给调点味
Then let me season it a bit
# 一勺（盐）再来一勺 两勺
One spoonful (salt) and one more spoonful two spoonful
# 三勺 让它稍微有点底味就行
Three spoons to give it a little bit of base taste
# 来点白胡椒
Some white pepper
# 来点葱姜
Some green onion and ginger
# 葱段
Shallots
# 齐活 让它稍微的煮一会儿
let it cook for a while
# 煮它十分八分的就行了
Just cook it for about 8-10 mins
# 其实过去老师傅传承下来
In fact, the master passed down this technique
# 贵妃的汁相对来讲简单
Gui Fei sauce is relatively simple
# 根据现在人的这个需求
According to the needs of people now
# 我们可以调新派的汁
We can make modern sauce
# 只要好吃就没问题
As long as it tastes good
# 好了十分钟到了二伯 关火吧
Alright, ten minutes later, Er Bo, turn off the heat
# 黄酒 网友们注意了 关了火加黄酒
Yellow wine, netizens pay attention to turn off the fire and add yellow wine
# 酒味就出来了
The taste of wine comes out
# 咱们弄浓一点
Let's make it thicker
# 洗着冰水浴的鸡 下锅
Ice-water bath and wash the chicken pot
# 师父这儿还有俩爪 扔进去
Master, there are still two claws here, throw them in
# 得嘞盖盖儿 咱先闷着吧 二十五分钟
You have to cover it, let it simmer for 25 minutes
# 关火浸熟
Turn off the heat and soak
# 这时候你来点吧 那我做个蘸料
At this time, you can do something. I'll make a dip
# 蘸料也很讲究 粤式吃法是用沙姜
Dips are very particular about among Cantonese. They use sand ginger
# 但是咱们家里边有这个大姜就使这个
But we have this normal ginger at home to make this
# 加点盐 加点盐就不滚了
Add some salt
# 你看这姜汁都出来了
Look, all this ginger juice is coming out
# 师父您看这个行吗 这差不多了
Master You see this all right this almost
# 你看这出来这汁就味浓
You see, the juice is strong
# 稍微来点小细葱花 齐活
Little bit of diced green onion to touch it up
# 我们烧一锅 要呲点油
Let's heat a pot of oil and pour some oil
# 这里边搁点盐 稍微来点盐
Put some salt here, some salt
# 让它有点底味
Give it a bit of base taste
# 师父我犯了个错误
Master, I made a mistake
# 应该先把姜蓉呲熟了 再搁小葱花 没事
The ginger should be cooked first and then the chopped green onions
# 咱们来点花生油香 花生油香啊
Let's have some peanut oil, peanut oil is fragrant
# 你再给他弄个豉油汁
You get him another soy sauce
# 直接花生油加蒸鱼豉油
Simply use peanut oil with steamed fish soy sauce
# 花生油呲出来也香
The peanut oil smells good
# 切两刀小米辣
Cut two knives millet spicy
# 找点香菜 稍微切点大梗
Find some coriander and cut some big stems
# 咱们给它倒进去 这样味道更香了
Let's pour it in so it smells more fragrant
# 轻轻地熬制 香味出来了
Simmer gently, the fragrance comes out
# 这叫一个香
This smells really good
# 齐活 两个汁 想吃哪个吃哪个
All done, two sauce, have whichever one you want to eat
# 黄瓜（胡萝卜）切成长方的东西
Cucumber (carrot) cut into long squares
# 白萝卜
White radish
# 这
# 鸡应该说是差不多了、
This chicken is almost done,
# 能扎进去了 不冒血水了 那就熟了
If you can poke through it without blood coming out then it’s all cooked
# 另外这个鸡实际上是越嫩越好吃师父
In addition, this chicken is actually more delicious if it’s more tender
# 捞出来了啊
getting it out
# 网友朋友们 冰又准备好了 降温皮更脆
Netizens and friends, the ice is ready again to cool the skin and make it crispier
# 再来点黄酒
Some more yellow wine
# 提提味 好啦
Bring out the flavor, Well that’s it
# 交给你了 好勒 这鸡已经好了
I'll leave it to you . alrighty, this chicken is ready
# 我先给它斩一下
I'll cut it first
# 头 对
Head right
# 放这儿
Put it here
# 码一鸡形就行
Just a chicken shape
# 顺着它这骨头剔出去 老菜必须得脱骨
Take the bone out of it, if this is cooked in the old fashion then the bones must be removed
# 然后怎么切呢
Then how to cut it
# 斜着片就为了夹这个 明白了吧
I sliced it at an angle so that it can wrap this, do you understand?
# 斜着片 大斜坡
Slice diagonally with a large slope
# 整个的片完了整个挪过来 必须得切开
After the whole film is finished, the whole move must be cut
# 一片萝卜 一片黄瓜
A slice of radish and a slice of cucumber
# 你就顺着这个码 码成一鸡形
You just follow this code to form a chicken shape
# 让它有点鸡的样
Make it look like a chicken
# 码一过桥 让它有个弧度
Make a bridge shape so that it has an arc
# 这就对了 这就行了
That's right, that's it
# 咱们浇点原汤进去 贵妃鸡
Let's pour some original soup in, royal chicken
# 清爽 颜色美观
Refreshing and beautiful colors
# 让它整个洇出来这汤 没这汤还真不好看
Let it bleed out of this soup, it would not look good without this soup
# 然后浇满了就行了 好嘞
Then poured over, all done
# 贵妃鸡
Gui Fei Chicken
# 还得配俩汁儿呐
You have to match with two sauces
# 大爷您看 蘸点儿汁儿吃
Uncle, look, dip some sauce and eat it
# 我先吃一个豉油汁的
I will have it with soy sauce first
# 皮脆 肉嫩 汁的味道十足
The skin is crispy and the tender meat is full of flavor
# 姜汁
Ginger sauce
# 大爷 地道
Da Ye this is authentic
# 评价的话
If I had to comment on this
# 姜汁比豉油汁香
Ginger sauce is more fragrant than soy sauce
# 回味无穷啊
Endless aftertaste
# 滑 嫩 弹 真棒
Slippery and tender this is so good
# 回眸一笑百媚生
One smile
# 后宫粉黛无颜色
Makes everyone else look less pretty
# 贵妃鸡
Gui Fei Chicken